[SPEAKER_00] As-salamu alaykum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatuhu, bismillahirrahmanirrahim, nahamaduhu, nusanni ala rasulil kareem, amma ba'al. Welcome back from break, you all look very excited to be back in class, you also look very stressed for the test. How many of us got a chance to study, you can be honest, I won't judge you, how many of us got a chance to study for the test and to break? Okay, not so many people, but okay. So I guess my plan didn't work, right? Okay, so at least we have two days to study, right? Or not even full two days, but yeah, we have less than 48 hours to study. Is that? Is that enough, Inshallah? Should we delay the test?
[SPEAKER_00] No, I'm sorry. No, we're already going too slow paced, you know, I mean, I expected us to be further than we are now, so we cannot delay the test anymore, Inshallah. We're just delaying the inevitable. You can make the test, and then you can make another test with people that want it too. What? I don't have time to make two tests, man. So, okay, let's see a raise of hands, although it's not a democracy, so even if there's a majority, I'm not bound by that majority, but just to see a general idea, how many people think we should delay the test? Oh, I heard a lot more voices when I said it before, but I think people, who thinks we should just have it, just have it on Wednesday? We should just do it today. Today? Some brother said we should just do it today. Okay,
[SPEAKER_00] now, Inshallah, we'll do it on Wednesday. Inshallah, don't need to stress, Inshallah, if you just, if you look at the number of pages in the book, it looks quite daunting, but just look at Brother Salim's review sheet, and it looks a lot easier. Oh, three pages, okay, I just need to, you know, if I get these three pages down, then I should be set, and it's true, Inshallah, like, it's very, very comprehensive, I'm going to look through it in detail, just a few feedbacks here and there, but overall, Inshallah, he did an amazing job of covering pretty, literally everything. Everything that we covered, right? Just, the only thing short is having the actual examples from the book, but other than that, literally every single thing, Hamza, I think that we did, yeah, maybe a few things here and there, but like small things, but I can't, I myself can't even remember, but I'm not sure he did an amazing job. So if you use that as your template, and then maybe look back at the book to see if there's something you want to, you know, like double check, or just see examples of, then that's fine, but I think, Inshallah, if you just take his vocabulary sheet, print it out, keep that in front of you. Um, and test yourself on it, then Inshallah, I think it should be
[SPEAKER_00] enough. All right, Inshallah? So for today's class, I honestly didn't plan anything specific. I wanted to leave it up to you guys. What I would prefer, my, my personal preference would be that you guys just review amongst yourselves, and I do my work, because I have a lot of work to do, um, and if you have any questions, I'm here, and I can answer any questions. That's what I would prefer, but if any of you, if you want, want to have an actual review again. Like, for a third time. Um, like, and you want me to go through all this stuff again, then you can do that, if you, if you really want to. So what do you guys think? Of the test? I would, but I personally don't even know what the test, I didn't, I didn't think of it yet, but, but I mean, just expect it kind of, well, last time it was vocabulary, specifically. So the vocabulary part might be similar to the last test. As for the, this test, okay, let me just give you a general idea. For the Mudaaf Mudaafideh, I'll just be straightforward. You have to know that in
[SPEAKER_00] and out, right? There's no excuses. As Brother Salim said, we spent like five weeks on Mudaaf Mudaafideh, so inshallah, that, nobody has any excuses of getting wrong, right? So know those five rules. I might, I'm probably just going to say, list out the five rules of Mudaaf Mudaafideh that we learned, right? So you really have to just know it by head, and just, again, you have, not word for word, but just a general gist of the, the, what those five, uh, rules are, right? So some might be like that. Mostly, I'm not going to do it like that. I'm just going to maybe test concepts. So if Mudaaf Mudaafideh, that's going to be there, and also, just to see if you guys get the concept, I might say, for example, put the haraka, for example, like, we put Kitab Muhammad, right? So I'm going to, just going to put this, like this. I'm going to tell you, put the haraka, like, harakat, so you have to put it like this. And this is, like, obviously, the main thing I'm going to focus on, Kitabu. And this, this is, like, the main thing. The other ones, obviously, hopefully, you get it right, it's fine, but the
[SPEAKER_00] main thing I'm going to be focusing on is this, to see if you got the concept of Mudaaf Mudaafideh. I might say also, okay, and translate it, right? I might just put something like this and say, translate this, right? What does this mean? To see if you understand it means the book of Muhammad, you know, entails possession, for example. Then there will be probably a question or two on the families. Again, I won't maybe necessarily ask you for the names of the families, but the concepts, right? For example, the Ism al-Ishaara, those words that indicate towards something, right? So, like, what does it entail? Like, how that entails something is closed and that, that, those things you should know. Sorry? Yeah. So, extra credit will probably be to name, like, the families and their names and stuff like that. That might be one extra credit question. I might have a couple, because this test is going to be intense. Inshallah. I won't make it hard, but you have to know your, what we studied,
[SPEAKER_00] you have to know it. Inshallah. Then, it'll be hard to get a hundred, right? And I'll challenge it. Yeah, it's a prize for those who get a hundred or more, inshallah, because obviously you have extra credit, so you have that chance as well. So, there'll be a special prize for those people, inshallah. And what that prize is will depend on how many people get it. If there's, like, ten people getting it, then obviously it'll be a little less. But, so yeah, so there will be something, inshallah. So, it won't be easy to get a hundred, but at the same time. Inshallah, it won't be so easy to fail either, right? Like, inshallah, try to, you know, make it such that it's manageable and, you know, if you get the concept overall, inshallah, you should be able to do it decently, but you should know your things properly. That's the main thing. What other things are there? Let me just look at this sheet, if there's any other things I can think of that I might be on a test. Let's see.
[SPEAKER_00] Did anybody not get that sheet? Maybe somebody checked their WhatsApp? Or some of them are not in the WhatsApp group? Just you? You didn't check. So, all you need to do is open up your phone, go on WhatsApp, and then, anybody else? You? You don't have WhatsApp? Is your father or somebody on their group or no? Huh? Should I put them in the group? Okay, I'll take your number later, but... So, for now, inshallah, if you want, we can have it printed for you. Do you want to... Yeah, could you do that? So, after class, I'll get it printed for you. Okay, so, no problem. Yeah, the vocabulary, again, will be similar to the previous. Yeah, other than that, I might ask you to list some aspects of the rules, but most... Yeah, like, for example, the verbs, right? So, خرج, so that means he left, but what does that entail, right? Remember we mentioned that
[SPEAKER_00] it entails that it's a male, singular, third person, past tense. So, you should know that, right? You should be able to list that out. For example, a kalima is divided into three parts, right? Ism, feral, and harf. So, you should know that and be able to very, very briefly just explain what it is, right? Even if you just translate noun, or, and then, like, feral is a verb. And harf. You could put particle if you just put a brief explanation of what it is. But just have that in your mind as well. Then, so, yeah, so, I would say, just looking at it now and thinking of it now, one of the sections of the test would just be putting حركات, right? Like, you know, you know what حركات is, right? Like, زبر زير بش, فتر كسر ضم. So, you're just going to have Arabic words that have no حركات on them. So, you have to put them based on what we learned, right? So, like... Things that I would be focusing on are, like, حرف الجر, right? So, if it comes after حرف الجر, then you have to make sure that
[SPEAKER_00] it's كسر. Right? So, you put that down. And then, مضاف مضاف في لي. So, make sure you don't put a تنوين on this, right? And don't make sure this is كسر, right? And then, what else? Yeah, those are the main things. Or even, like, for example, ياء, right? ياء محمدو, right? So, make sure you don't put ياء محمدن, for example, right? So, that would be a whole question. That would be a decent amount. A lot of points. So, that's something to keep in mind. Make sure you know how to implement all the rules and how they practically look in terms of the حركة. That's a good idea. I wasn't thinking of that, but it's a good idea, mashallah. Yeah. We might do that, inshallah. Yeah, that's not a bad idea. Actually, because that was one of the exercises in here, too, that this is incorrect. So, put it correctly. So, good idea. Another question there will be about is about male, masculine, and feminine things, right? So, things like, for
[SPEAKER_00] example, oh, yeah, another thing to keep in mind is فاطمة, too. Remember, female names, they don't have to mean, right? So, that also, for the حركة part, that would also be tested as well. Then, for female, right? So, remember we mentioned that, for example, if you're describing a female, you put تا مربوطة, right? Right. That there are certain words, they're female, but there's no تا مربوطة on them, right? So, those will be tested, too, somehow. Like, for example, I might just say that turn this sentence, it's a male sentence, turn it to a female sentence. So, I'm going to be testing, for example, the male sentence will be هَذَا الرَّجُلُ طَوِينٌ This man is tall. So, then, you would have to change that into a female version. And this is a good example, because I know we didn't learn the female counterpart of رَجُل. It's اِمْرَأَة. But we didn't. We didn't learn that yet. But I'm just saying, something along those lines. Or you could just say فَاطِمَةَ طَوِيلَتُنْ Right? So, just make sure you're putting تُنْ So, just the concept of
[SPEAKER_00] knowing that female things have تَا مَرْبُطَةِينَ So, that's also a concept that will be tested, inshallah. What else? I'm not going to tell you, like, oh, that's too much work. Like, all the 14 moon letters. But, yeah, I mean, that's more of like a reading thing. So, it's kind of hard for me to test you unless I... I tell you لِصَالَم what I don't... Which I don't want to do. As long as when you're reading it, you understand those things. So, what do you guys think? Or maybe I could just do, like, for example, رَجُلُ Is this... Is there... Is this شَمْسِي or حَرَقَمَرِي? Maybe I could do something like that. Okay, so maybe I'll do something like that. No? You're حافظ. This should be easy for you. Oh, they said no. Oh, you said no. You're also حافظ. Oh, he said no. Somebody said no, okay. Okay, anyways.
[SPEAKER_00] Sorry? حَمْلِتُ الْوَصُل Well, maybe I might ask you to explain the concept. Like, write down the concept. But, like, you can only test it if you read it, right? Because that's a reading issue. So, there's no way I could really test you on it. Unless you want to do an oral section of the test, too. Yeah. But, I just want to, on test day, I just want to relax and just watch you guys stress. So, I don't think I want to have an oral part, so. We can have a separate oral test sometime online, inshallah. Sometime soon. Maybe before Ramadan or something. Yeah, that's not a bad idea. We'll do that, inshallah. Wait, do we have class in Ramadan? No. No. Okay. One extra question. Extra credit might be, list the words that don't end with ta marbuta but are still feminine. That might be extra credit.
[SPEAKER_00] Maybe. And, what else? Yeah, so I think that should give you a general idea of how the test might be. So, accordingly. In general, you can just keep the, you know, the exercise that are in the book itself. You can just look at it. You can just look at how those are formulated. I might just take the concept of those and then just change, bring my own examples or something like that. You know, like fill in the blanks, for example. But, things like that. I might just look from there and take examples from there, so. To what extent do we need to know, like, exceptions to rules like love and hate? I mean, I didn't teach you. I just told you that there are exceptions, right? I didn't teach you what the exceptions are. Okay. So, I'm obviously not going to put a, hopefully I'm not going to put a, a question, a test that entails that you know that this is an exception. So, I'm just going to put, that's what, like, that's what they do in the book too, right? They normally don't put the exceptions in
[SPEAKER_00] the, in the book for, for now until those are introduced. We just came across exceptions because we're bringing things from the Quran and stuff like that. Okay, inshallah. So, that's, everybody kind of got an overall idea of how the test is going to be? Inshallah. So, here's a question. If the person gets 100, what is the probability? I tell you, I don't know. I don't even know myself yet. But, but, it also depends on how many people are going to get 100, right? So, if all of you guys get 100, then the prize will be much smaller, right? If one person gets 100, then maybe it will be a nice prize, so. So, we'll see, inshallah. Say it again? I mean, like, a three-way review session right now? In what sense? Three people are reviewing together. Oh. I could just leave it open. Like, you don't have to, like, whoever wants to review with others. Because some people are different, right? Some people, they, they work better on their own.
[SPEAKER_00] Like, they, they kind of just lock in by themselves. They can study on their own. Some people work better when they work in groups. So, we can just leave it open. And whoever wants to sit with others, they can sit with others. Everybody's going to gather around Salim. They're going to be like, oh, teach me. Because, you know, he got the, the experience. He got experience with the vocabulary. And again, I'm here. I'm here if I have any, if you have any questions. Unless, did somebody want me to explain all those things again, or? Just one question. I think I asked this before, but I just didn't think yet. So, is it, because normally you would put one kasra, right? Because it's a name you're putting in two kasras? Is that? No. So, you would only put one kasra if there's an al there. Okay. You get it? Because remember, al and tanween can never come together. Okay. So, that's why we're putting, we're putting, there's no al over here. Okay. So, it's two. So, it's just simple. If there's no al, then you would put two kasras. If there's al, then you put one. Yeah. For the male. Sorry? For the male. For the? For the male. Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00] For the male names, yeah. For female names, it would be an exception. It would actually end, it would actually be, just to tell you guys, you don't have to know this, but there's a lesson that will come soon. It will be kitabu fa'atimatta. And that, we won't even get a kasra at all. But that, we'll get to later, inshallah. So, we, that won't be asked. We won't be asking you or something like that. Is that a gender rule for female names? Yeah. Okay. It has to do with the same reason why we say fa'atimattu and not fa'atimattun. Okay. There's certain words that cannot get kasra and tanween. Okay. So, then they just become a fatha when they get a kasra. So, but that, inshallah, will come later. Okay. So, anything else? So, this example, kitabu muhammadin or muhammadin? Muhammadin, because it's tanween. Yeah. Why is it not muhammadin? Because, as I mentioned, there's no al, right? Because if there's an al,
[SPEAKER_00] then there won't be a tanween. But because there's no al, then there is a tanween. Right. Anything else? No, because muhammad, you don't put al. You don't say al muhammad. You just say muhammad. Yeah. Okay. Okay. Could it be ya muhammadi? Or it has to be ya muhammadu? We learned this already. Remember, if you have ya, then it will always have a dhamma on the word after it. Yeah. With regards to your question, sorry, one second. So, names in general won't have al on them, right? Because remember we mentioned that, as Prophet Sallallahu Alaihi Wasallam also put on the review sheet, that names in English are called proper nouns, right? Meaning they're already specified. So, it's already talking about a specific person. So, muhammad is talking about a specific person, so there's no need for al, because the purpose of al is to make something specific. So, if you're putting al and then you put a name, it's like you're making it
[SPEAKER_00] double specific. So, there's no point. So, there's very, very, very few names that have al that's only exception in Arabic language. Like, an example is al-Hasan, al-Hasan al-Basri, al-Husayn, right? So, these are certain exceptional names, al-Hadith, there's a few names in Arabic that are just known as an exception. The Arabic language that take, that have al in the beginning. Otherwise, names in general don't have al in the beginning. Number of people who have, like, amtul wahaab, so that is an exception. Yeah, that's an exception, yeah, yeah. I mean, that's not an exception, but it's just the slave of blank, so that's different. I have a question regarding the Badr Saleem's sheet. Somebody has printed, I don't know what color is that, because I have black and white only. So, like, I cannot see these, I don't know. Can you make this in gold, so it can print better, or? Maybe you could just try printing in color if you have, or? I just have another printer. Okay.
[SPEAKER_00] I can, I can print in black and white, sir. See, like. Because it might be a lot of work, right, or? No, I just use a phone. Okay. All right. I just have a basic printer. Which one? Just how many? Two. When you zoom in, it doesn't accommodate it. It doesn't fit in. Zoom. When did you print that? Today. Okay. Okay. So, I'm going to try it today. Okay. MashaAllah, Brother Saleem put in a lot of time, like, like weeks, MashaAllah, on this, on this sheet. So everyone, please make dua for Brother Saleem. May Allah grant him barakah in his time, in his family, in his wealth, in his health. Let's all make dua for him, inshaAllah. MashaAllah. Brother Saleem, that's how it's supposed to come? Like, this small? On the page? I mean, I have to, it's different applications I use. So I use OneNote and then when I print, I print it. And then when it comes ready to a PDF, the sizing and the format changes. So, I can't send it to you in OneNote because you guys don't have it. Most of us don't have OneNote. I just print it from wherever you send it. Okay. So at this point, inshaAllah,
[SPEAKER_00] I think, since everybody's here, I hope nobody's thinking that, oh, why did I come to class today? We're not even doing class. But I brought you guys here so that, to make sure you guys study, because if I gave a day off today, I know nobody would study, right? So at least you have these 20 minutes to study rather than having zero time and you fail on Wednesday, right? Yeah. So obviously you should study at home. But if you don't, then at least you have this time. So whatever questions you can ask, oh. Okay. So what they were saying about, we can't say, I think, Kitab Allahi, but Kitab Muhammadin. Is that correct, right? Yeah, that's correct. When they say there's no Tanween. Tanween. Yeah. That's because Allah, remember I explained to you guys how Allah is actually Al, you know, Ilah, right? But then due to some things that we don't have to go into now, it turned into Allah. So technically it does have Al in it. That's why you don't say Allahin, you say
[SPEAKER_00] Allahi. That's why I say it. Yeah. I took it as an example of the word. Oh, okay. You gave me an example. Okay, inshallah. So anybody else have any questions, inshallah, you can ask me directly so other people can have time to, you know, study, inshallah. So everybody can study either in groups or on their own, inshallah. Or everybody can just come to work. Maybe brother Salim and just bombard him. You already gave enough time, inshallah, on this sheet. Also how many of us did the handwriting homework? Everybody was asking me every other day about when we're getting the handwriting books, handwriting books, and when it comes, nobody even does it. The amount of times I bothered Umar, brother Umar about the handwriting books just because brothers were asking me and nobody does it. Come on. Take the books back. See you next time. I swear. Okay, shall everybody can start studying? Okay. Go ahead.
[SPEAKER_00] Okay.